现在让我们谈谈我们如何计算立体差异。我们拍了一对照片
Let's talk now about how we compute stereo disparity. We have a pair of images taken
通过立体相机。我们有左图像和右图像，我们的目标是计算
by a stereo camera. We have a left image and a right image, and our goal is to compute
我们称之为视差图像。在视差图像中，像素的亮度对应
what we call a disparity image. In the disparity image, the brightness of a pixel corresponds
到该特定点的立体差异。
to the stereo disparity at that particular point.
明亮的点具有大的立体差异，并且当对象出现时发生
A point that's bright has got a large stereo disparity and that occurs when an object is
靠近我们，较暗的像素具有较小的视差并对应于一个物体
close to us, and a darker pixel has got a smaller disparity and corresponds to an object
那是更远的地方。我们想要了解我们如何能够采用原始的左右
that is further away. We want to understand how we can take that original left and right
图像，处理它并将其转换为此视差图像。这种计算的基本原理
image, process it and turn it into this disparity image. The fundamental principle of this computational
立体声可以很简单地描述。
stereo can be described quite simply.
这是我从埃菲尔铁塔略有不同的观点拍摄的两张照片。
Here are two pictures that I took of the Eiffel Tower from slightly different viewpoints.
让我们考虑一下塔顶的一个点。我打算选择一个窗口
Let's consider a single point on the top of the tower. I'm going to select a window of
周围的像素，我将打印那个像素窗口的副本
pixels around that, and I'm going to make a copy of that window of pixels and there
它在顶部。
it is at the top.
现在我要将距离U转移到右手图像并做一点点
Now I'm going to transfer the distance U to the right hand image and do a little bit of
施工。我要说的是，我所寻找的差距已经达到最大值
construction. I am going to say that the disparity that I am looking for has got a maximum value
我打电话给D-max。现在，立体声过程涉及寻找那个小模板
that I'm going to call D-max. Now, the stereo process involves looking for that little template
埃菲尔铁塔顶部沿着该搜索线的每个可能的位置和最好的
of the top of the Eiffel Tower at every possible position along that search line and the best
这个特定的位置显然是合适的，距离垂直方向的距离为D.
fit is clearly at this particular location, which is a distance D away from the vertical
我画的参考线。
reference line that I drew.
D是此时的差异值。显然，这是一个计算密集型
D is the value of the disparity at this point. Clearly this is quite a computationally intensive
处理。我必须在许多不同的可能差异值上进行模板匹配
process. I have to do a template match at a number of different possible disparity values
从零到D-max。这只是为了确定坐标U，V处的视差。
from zero up to D-max. And this is just to determine the disparity at the coordinate U, V.
我实际上需要为输入图像中的每个像素执行此操作。这当然是
I actually need to do this for every single pixel in the input image. It is certainly
很多计算，但是对于今天的计算机来说，它可以非常非常快速地完成
a lot of computation, but with today's computers it can be done very, very quickly even for
非常高分辨率的立体图像对。
very high resolution stereo image pairs.
让我们将立体声对加载到我们的工作区中。我要从中加载左图像
Let's load a stereo pair into our workspace. I'm going to load the left image from the
文件rocks2-L，我要从rocks2-R加载正确的图像。我使用了reduce选项
file rocks2-L and I'm going to load the right image from rocks2-R. I've used the reduce option
在水平和垂直方向上读取分辨率因为它们非常，
to iread the resolution in the horizontal and vertical direction because these are very,
在MATLAB下，非常高分辨率的图像和立体声计算有点慢。
very high-resolution images and the stereo computation is a little slow under MATLAB.
我要做的第一件事就是将图像显示为立体图像。通过左边
The first thing I’m going to do is to display the images as an anaglyph. Pass the left
和图像到立体照片功能，在这里我们看到一个立体图像
and right images to the anaglyph function and here we see an anaglyph representation
一堆岩石的立体声场景。如果我戴上红色和蓝色眼镜，就可以了
of this stereo scene of a pile of rocks. If I had my red and blue glasses on, this would
看起来非常有力的三维。
look very powerfully three-dimensional.
让我们更详细地看一下左右图像。我要去
Let’s have a look at the left and right images in a bit more detail. I’m going to
使用工具箱功能，stdisp，立体显示，它给出了一个看起来像的窗口
use the toolbox function, stdisp, stereo display and it gives a window that looks something
像这样，我只是想让它更广泛一点。
like this and I’m just going to make that a little bit wider.
现在，我们在这里看到左图和右图。让我点击一个特定点
Now, here we see the left image and the right image. Let me just click on a particular point
在图像中。我要点击前景中的这块岩石。我要点击了
in the image. I’m going to click on this rock in the foreground. I’m going to click
在那个特定的斑点上，如果我去另一个图像，那是相同的斑点;
on that particular blotch there and if I go to the other image and that’s the same blotch;
就在那里，
it’s just there,
我要点击它并在顶部我们看到左边病房的差异
I’m going to click on it and up the top we see the disparity that is the left ward
在右图中移位，它是79.29像素。现在让我们看一下
shift in the right image and it’s 79.29 pixels. Now let’s have a look at a point
在背上。让我们来看看这两块岩石之间这个非常独特的山谷
on the back. Let’s have a look at this very distinctive valley between these two rocks
然后点击该点。
and click on that point.
我将在另一个图像中找到相同的点，它就在那里，现在
I’m going to find the same point in the other image and it’s just there and now
我们看到差距，左边的病房转移已经减少。它只有43.45像素。
we see that the disparity, the left ward shift has been reduced. It’s only 43.45 pixels.
让我们找到一个介于这些事物之间的点。我们来看一下
Let’s find a point that’s somewhere in between those things. Let’s have a look
在这个白点，我们在正确的图像中找到它。就在那里。在这种情况下，
at this white dot here and we find it in the right image. It’s just there. In this case,
差异是52像素。
the disparity is 52 pixels.
所以我们可以非常清楚地看到深度和差异之间的关系。积分在
So we can see very clearly the relationship between depth and disparity. Points in the
前景有很大的差距。背景中的点数差异要小得多。
foreground have got a large disparity. Points in the background have got a much smaller disparity.
现在让我们计算这对图像中每个像素的视差。我要去
Now let’s compute disparity for every single pixel in this pair of images. I’m going
将差异放入工作空间变量D.我将使用工具箱函数
to put the disparity into the workspace variable D. I’m going to use the toolbox function
istereo并传递左图像和右图像。
istereo and pass in the left image and the right image.
差异的范围是搜索这个特定的对，我已经解决了
The range of disparity is to search over and for this particular pair, I've worked out
最小视差是40像素，最大视差是90像素，我是
that the smallest disparity is 40 pixels and the largest disparity is 90 pixels and I’m
传递匹配窗口的半宽。匹配窗口将是三次
passing the half width of the matching window. The matching window will be three times two
加一。那是一个七乘七的窗口。
plus one. That’s a seven by seven window.
计算需要一两个时间，现在我可以在这里显示视差图像
Computation takes a moment or two and now I can display the disparity image and here
我们看到了。如果我可以点击这里的一些像素，我们在前景中看到这里的岩石有
we see it. If I can click on some pixels here we see in the foreground this rock here has
从世界各地的相应点开始，大约有83个差距开始出现
got disparities starting off around 83 falling away as the corresponding points in the world
离相机越来越远，跌到70多岁。这些岩石在这里晃动
get further away from the camera, falls off to 70 something. These rocks up the back here
有一个小得多的差距，50的顺序。这个摇滚的东西像40和
have got a much smaller disparity, the order of 50. This rock’s something like 40 and
这些真正黑暗的背后有45或46的差距。
these really dark ones up the back have a disparity of 45 or 46.
我们可以看到这张图片远非完美。有些观点看起来不太好看
We can see that this image is far from perfect. There are some points that just don’t look
对。岩石边缘周围有一些非常异常的亮点，那就是
right. There are some very anomalous bright points around the edges of the rocks and that’s
因为从一个摄像机视图可以看到岩石的那些部分，但是从中看不到
because those parts of the rock are visible from one camera view but not visible from
另一个摄像机视图，这意味着无法正确完成立体声匹配。
the other camera view and that means that the stereo matching can’t be completed properly.
您还注意到图像侧面有一个黑色区域，就在那里
You also note that there’s a black region down the side of the image and that’s where
相机的视野不完全重叠。这是一个非常简单的立体视觉
the fields of view of a camera don’t fully overlap. This is a very simplistic stereovision
算法。有更复杂的技术，但它证明了原理。
algorithm. There are much more sophisticated techniques available but it demonstrates the principle.